<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Theoretical course Level 4 FFV on Dinghy - FFV4</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/</link><description>Recent content in Theoretical course Level 4 FFV on Dinghy - FFV4</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Appendix: Recognizing clouds</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/clouds_recognition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/clouds_recognition/</guid><description>A distinction is made between layered or stratiform clouds and ball or cumuliform clouds.
On the altitude side, the names of the highest clouds are composed with the prefix &amp;ldquo;cirro&amp;rdquo;, those of medium altitude with the prefix &amp;ldquo;alto&amp;quot;:
in the lower stage (from the ground to 2 km altitude), we encounter stratus (S) and stratocumulus (Sc). in the middle stage (from 2 to 5 or even 7 km of altitude), the altocumulus (Ac) and the altostratus (As).</description></item><item><title>Appendix: the fronts</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/annexe-fronts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/annexe-fronts/</guid><description>Source: lavionnaire.fr
Definition # It is a region of the troposphere constituting a dynamic and thermal transition zone between two air masses different by their characteristics. Source : Météo-France A front is a surface of discontinuity (transition zone) where two air masses with different properties confront each other. There are different types of fronts:
warm fronts, cold fronts, occluded fronts, stationary fronts. Front schema
Representing fronts on maps # Here are the official symbols used to represent fronts on color or black and white weather maps.</description></item><item><title>General circulation</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/general_circulation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/general_circulation/</guid><description>General Circulation # Explanation of temperature differences on earth # Earth-sun diagram
The sun provides almost all of our energy.
The energy balance of the Earth is zero: the Earth sends back into space all the energy it receives.
However, the energy received by the Earth is not uniform depending on the latitude.
The equator receives more energy than the poles. This will create warmer and colder areas.</description></item><item><title>Getting a good start</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/getting_off_to_a_good_start/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/getting_off_to_a_good_start/</guid><description>A good start consists in crossing the line as soon as possible after the start. But it is not enough, you also have to start: that is to say with as much speed as possible.
You must observe the other competitors and the elements (wind, currents) and use them to your advantage.
Here is a video that explains how to position yourself for a starboard tack start. In the video below, you can see the importance of starting with speed, when all the racers are grouped together on the line, they are all sailing in a shifty, turbulent wind.</description></item><item><title>Resalage</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/resalage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/resalage/</guid><description>Assessing the situation # Desalting is not a trivial matter. Depending on the conditions, you can hurt (and scare) yourself.
As soon as you surface, check for any loose ends or other objects that may be in your way. Locate where you are on the water and the time available for resurfacing: rocks, other boat. If you feel that you do not have the time to right the boat in the face of danger, give priority to people over equipment.</description></item><item><title>Self-evaluation</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/self-evaluation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/self-evaluation/</guid><description>This is the evaluation framework of the Fédération Française de Voile.
It is important to take your time and move on to the next level when you have mastered the previous one perfectly because the steps are designed to be consistent with the learning progression. But keep in mind that this is only a guide, and everyone progresses differently.
Be humble, there is no point in working on regatta strategies if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how to do a tack and master the exit angle, going backwards can allow you to &amp;ldquo;back up to jump&amp;rdquo; and ultimately make your progress faster.</description></item><item><title>The dynamic settings</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/settings/dynamics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/settings/dynamics/</guid><description>Listening # Explained to a beginner trainee... The sheet is used to adjust the angle of the sail in relation to the wind, it is the one that ensures the propulsion of the sailboat. It is used to propel the sailboat. It is trimmed upwind and trimmed downwind.
To trim upwind: we observe the sail&amp;rsquo;s flutter, as soon as it appears, we trim a little to erase it.</description></item><item><title>The flows</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/dinghy_mecanic/flows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/dinghy_mecanic/flows/</guid><description>A flow is the movement of a fluid. A streamline is the materialization of the movement of the fluid in a flow.
There are 2 types of flows:
Laminar: the current lines are almost parallel to each other. Vortex: the current lines are totally disordered. The sails of a sports dinghy are most effective when the flow is laminar. It is highlighted by the penons and favors.
Penons</description></item><item><title>Appendix: Rigging a laser</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/laser_rigging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/laser_rigging/</guid><description>Prepare the sail # Place the material on a flat surface and check that you are not missing any parts Unroll the sail Thread the mast bottom and top in the axis, the two arrows must be aligned Slide the sail on the mast, the tack must be on the axis of the arrows and the mullet screw Put the battens in their respective places, the smallest on top.</description></item><item><title>Calculation of the water level</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/tides/water_height_calculation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/tides/water_height_calculation/</guid><description>The interest for the sailor is to know if there is enough water to sail. Even with a shallow draft, it is good to know where you can pass or not. This can allow you to make a short cut or to manage a sensitive channel.
It is imperative to remain critical of the calculations and verify them empirically. A frequent error is the inversion between rising and falling tide.</description></item><item><title>Change of speed with real wind fixed</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/winds/changing_speed_with_fixed_real_wind_speed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/winds/changing_speed_with_fixed_real_wind_speed/</guid><description>Adjusting the sails in case of speed change # We consider a steady current wind and a steady true wind. What happens when a dinghy accelerates and when it slows down?
Acceleration : wind speed (vv) that increases Slowing down: wind speed (vv) that decreases Close-up speed # Vectors
Vectors
Upwind, if you accelerate, the apparent wind increases and refuses.</description></item><item><title>Forces</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/dinghy_mecanic/strengths/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/dinghy_mecanic/strengths/</guid><description>Aerodynamic force / velocity force # Component of the velocity force # The aerodynamic force or vellic force is the sum of an infinite number of elementary &amp;ldquo;small forces&amp;rdquo;. Aero force
The resultant force is applied at the maximum of the trough and is almost perpendicular to the chord (except for incidence angles below 25°).
Sail efficiency # Velic polar
The angles that run through the curve are those of the apparent wind relative to the sailboat&amp;rsquo;s course.</description></item><item><title>Main rules</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/main_rules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/main_rules/</guid><description>Helm privileges # Rule 10 - Starboard tack priority # The sailboat in black shall not force the white to maneuver
When two sailboats pass each other while sailing in opposite directions, the one on starboard tack (receiving the wind from starboard) has priority. The sailboat on the port tack must then maneuver so as not to interfere with the other. Rule 11 - Leeward Priority # The windward sailboat shall not interfere with the leeward sailboat</description></item><item><title>Position of the crew</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/settings/positions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/settings/positions/</guid><description>The crew position is fundamentally important for the performance of the dinghy. It is therefore important to set it correctly.
Points of sail Longitudinal balance Lateral balance Close-hauled Forward Flat Close-hauled (light air) Forward Ahead slightly heeled Beam Reaching Centered Flat Breeze on the back Backward Counter-heeled Breeze on the back (light air) Backward Flat</description></item><item><title>Statics settings</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/settings/statics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/settings/statics/</guid><description>On the laser, only the choice of sail (Standard, Radial or 4.7) is a static setting, everything else is a dynamic setting.
More informations... You will find more information on &amp;ldquo;How to rig a laser&amp;rdquo; in the appendix.
How to rig a laser dinghy Difference between the different laser sails
Laser 4.7
Laser radial
Laser standard</description></item><item><title>The wind</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/wind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/wind/</guid><description>Balance of the winds # Wind is a flow of air. It moves globally from high pressure to low pressure. The greater the difference (gradient) in pressure (for a given distance), the stronger the wind. Pressure difference
Influence of the Coriolis force # Isobaric map
The wind moves parallel to the isobars (without taking friction into account): this is the geostrophic wind: balance between the pressure forces and the Coriolis force.</description></item><item><title>Air masses</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/air_volumes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/air_volumes/</guid><description>Here are the main air masses found in Western Europe that shape the weather we have.
Definition of a stable and unstable air mass # In the atmosphere, air that rises or sinks because it is forced to do so is said to be unstable. If it does not move vertically, or only slightly, it is said to be stable. Thus, if we heat air, its tendency will be to rise, it becomes unstable.</description></item><item><title>Bearing away from the buoy</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/abattee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/abattee/</guid><description>Chronology # Slaughtered at the Buoy
display_reading_time: true display_share_buttons: true navigation:
&amp;ldquo;/docs/chronologies/tacking_and_gybing&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;/docs/chronologies&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;/docs/chronologies/oloffee&amp;rdquo; Preparation: Put on the clear sheet Shock the hale low Slaughter: Slaughter and shock high End of the run: Raise the vertical stabilizer Start counter-heeling Trim from the edge Choke the cuningham Resume low pitch Think of tightening the buoy like a Formula 1 driver: with too tight a turn entry, you lose speed.</description></item><item><title>Oloffee at the buoy</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/oloffee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/oloffee/</guid><description>Chronology # Oloffee at the Buoy
display_reading_time: true display_share_buttons: true navigation:
&amp;ldquo;/docs/chronologies/abattee&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;/docs/chronologies&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;/docs/chronologies/resalage&amp;rdquo; Descent: Reef in to arrive under the correct tack. Preparation: Put the daggerboard back on Take up the edge Take up the cuningham Oloffee: Border the sheet Loffer End of the oloffee Resume low hale Remember to tighten the buoy like a Formula 1 driver: with a too tight turn entry, you lose speed.</description></item><item><title>Passing a reef</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/winds/gust_of_wind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/winds/gust_of_wind/</guid><description>A reef is an increase in the actual wind. This chart can be taken the other way around for the passage of a squall (but we try to avoid them). A strengthening wind (while remaining stable in direction) makes the apparent wind increase. The boat&amp;rsquo;s objective is to take the most direct route.
Upwind Increasing force:
You shock a little - You maintain the course - bends. If the true wind is too strong, the apparent wind (will) give way without being able to hold the boat and one must then loaf or shock.</description></item><item><title>Regatta flags</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/flags/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/flags/</guid><description>The race committee symbolizes one end of the starting line - on land or at sea. The orange flag indicates that the line is anchored. A buoy establishes the other end.
From one regatta to another, the duration of the starting procedure may vary. Most often, it is a countdown in minutes.
The race committee will conduct the starting procedure using flags and sound signals, in accordance with the &amp;ldquo;Instructions of Sailing&amp;rdquo; (IC) which must be broadcast to all.</description></item><item><title>Tacking and gybing</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/tacking_and_gybing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/tacking_and_gybing/</guid><description>Tacking and gybing are the basic dinghy maneuvers. We differentiate between classic maneuvers and rocking maneuvers. Tilting is an exaggeration of what is done naturally in strong winds. All you have to do is reproduce this movement.
Tacking # The tack is a strategic maneuver in dinghy sailing, it can make you lose or gain places. Often during a wind shift, the correct execution of a tack can give you an advantage over your competitors.</description></item><item><title>The balances</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/dinghy_mecanic/balance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/dinghy_mecanic/balance/</guid><description>Static balances # The center of gravity # The drifter has a center of gravity noted
\(CG\) , like any object entering the field of attraction of a planet, point of application of Newton's force: Gravity. This force is exerted vertically from top to bottom.
If we take the dinghy alone (without its crew), its center of gravity is invariable whatever the position of the boat.</description></item><item><title>Clouds</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/clouds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/clouds/</guid><description>A cloud is composed of water or ice droplets. The air is completely saturated.
Types of cooling # To saturate air (at almost constant pressure), it must be cooled. There are 4 types of cooling:
Frontal Frontal cooling
Two air masses of different properties (warm and cold) meet. They do not mix. The warmer one is forced to rise (it is the lighter one). As it rises, it cools and condenses.</description></item><item><title>Direct and indirect links</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/dinghy_mecanic/direct-indirect-links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/dinghy_mecanic/direct-indirect-links/</guid><description>Direct links # mermaid.initialize({ "flowchart": { "useMaxWidth":true }, "theme": "default" } ) stateDiagram Helm -- Direction Sail -- Propulsion Weight -- Balance The helm affects the direction: If I put my helm to the left or right, I luff or pull down. The sails affect propulsion: If I put a lot of sail area, I have a lot of power, I move faster. The weight of the crew affects the balance: If I put the weight on one side the boat heels more or less.</description></item><item><title>Laylines</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/laylines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/laylines/</guid><description>The frame # During a regatta you can imagine a diamond between the windward and the leeward buoy: the frame.
This frame designates the limit course from which we make excess course. Within the frame, not all routes are equal, indeed, when tacking we lose some time and speed.
The frame designates the most direct route for the least number of maneuvers
If you want to reach the windward buoy with a single tack, the route taken will be the edge of the frame.</description></item><item><title>Frontology</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/frontology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/frontology/</guid><description>The front # A front is a region of the troposphere constituting a dynamic and thermal transition zone between two air masses with different characteristics (Source: Météo-France).
A front is a surface of discontinuity (transition zone) where two air masses with different properties confront each other. There are different types of fronts:
warm fronts, cold fronts, occluded fronts, stationary fronts. cold front Cold front
Cold air, which by its dynamics, meets warmer air.</description></item><item><title>Man overboard</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/man_overboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/man_overboard/</guid><description>General # Recovering a HLM is not a trivial task under any circumstances.
The mass of a laser with its crew is around 150 kg. Even at a few knots, on the head of a person in the water the shock can be fatal. If the HLM has fallen into the water conscious you will want to recover it consciously.
The HLM is a maneuver to be adapted according to the conditions, it will be necessary to adapt, you will be the only judge.</description></item><item><title>Taking the mast</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/mast_grabbing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/mast_grabbing/</guid><description>In some cases (crew too light and tired, need to go fast&amp;hellip;) it is necessary to help a boat to resalt by lifting its mast from the water.
This maneuver is quite technical and usually reserved for the instructor.
Poorly executed, it can become dangerous. Before attempting it, be sure you know how to stop at a specific point.
Depending on the position of the desalinated boat, arrive so that it finishes its maneuver facing the wind.</description></item><item><title>The proper use of a motorboat</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/motorboat_usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/motorboat_usage/</guid><description>Before starting the engine # Do a check-up of the boat # All lines are coiled and stowed. No lines are dragging in the water. Hull plugs are closed. Moorings are securely stowed. Check the engine # The feeder is full and connected to the engine. The vent (small opening on the fuel cap allowing air to enter) is open. The fuel supply is clear (no knots, pinching of the hose&amp;hellip;) The circuit breaker is in place.</description></item><item><title>Dinghy: Anchoring your safety boat</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/safety_boat_mooring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/safety_boat_mooring/</guid><description>To anchor your boat, you generally have two moorings:
A main anchor, heavy, at the front, consisting of an anchor with its chain and line, a line struck at the front of the boat. A secondary, light anchor, at the stern, consisting of a small anchor and a line. Remember that what ensures that an anchor holds well is not so much the anchor as the length of chain placed on the bottom.</description></item><item><title>Time associated with a disturbance</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/weather_associated_with_a_perturbation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/weather_associated_with_a_perturbation/</guid><description>Satellite view of a depression # Cold front
Disruption seen from above
Very often, the cloud structure of a disturbance allows you to distinguish several parts. The head is located in front of the disturbance. The body corresponds closely to the fronts. The warm sector is the warm air trapped between the warm and cold fronts.
Finally, the trail is located behind the cold front.</description></item><item><title>Towing after a dismasting</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/dematage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/dematage/</guid><description>It happens that the dinghy dismasts, it can happen because of a mast breakage (on the laser at the sleeve) or because of a mast foot breakage. In any case, it is impressive and should not be taken lightly.
Preparation of the tow # The list of operations to perform (this list is not exhaustive):
Make sure all crew are okay. Check where the current is coming from. Set the grappling hook in operation.</description></item><item><title>Isobaric map</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/isobaric_map/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/isobaric_map/</guid><description>Presentation # The isobaric map represents the current or forecasted barometric situation with the position of the fronts. There are several types of maps: the surface map (which represents the pressure at sea level) and the altitude maps (representing the geopotential altitude at a given pressure), however the altitude maps are more complex to interpret. A surface isobaric map can be plotted, that is, with wind and pressure readings.</description></item><item><title>Local weather</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/local_weather/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/local_weather/</guid><description>The coastal thermal breeze # The coastal thermal breezes are related to the interaction water / land: the thermal capacities of water and land are very different, they will therefore heat and cool at different speeds.
The sea is almost stable in temperature over 24 hours, while the land heats up during the day and cools down at night. This difference in temperature is at the origin of the breeze.</description></item><item><title>Modèles méteo</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/weather_models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/weather_models/</guid><description>Meteorological models are tools that allow us to predict the evolution of weather in the future.
They are based on complex mathematical calculations that take into account current conditions and wind and wave forecasts.
They are used by sailors to predict sailing conditions and by racers to predict race conditions.
Les informations à rechercher # L&amp;rsquo;origine # Weather models are produced by national or international weather services. One can assume a higher reliability depending on the proximity, but one should always check the forecasts with other sources.</description></item><item><title>The waves and the swell</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/waves_and_swell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/waves_and_swell/</guid><description>Definitions # Swell: sea of wind that has left its generating area Wave: sea of local wind The fetch is the distance over which the wind acts to create the waves. Wave length: distance between two crests of a wave train Formation # Birth of swell and waves
Creation of waves over the entirety of the world&amp;rsquo;s seas After the wind weakens or the waves spread outside the windy area, they spread freely, which is then called the swell Modification of waves in the vicinity of the coast by the presence of the bottom; As soon as the sea depth is less than about twice the height of the waves, they break on the beach or shoals.</description></item><item><title>The weather report</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/weather_report/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/weather_report/</guid><description>In order to help the sailor know what the weather will be like, each country is required to have a weather service. MétéoFrance issues weather reports on a regular basis (see MétéoFranceMarine Guide).
There are 4 types of bulletins according to the type of activity: shore, coast, open sea and open sea. The coastal bulletin is the one we are interested in. This bulletin is issued by a CROSS three times a day by VHF.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/icons-credits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/icons-credits/</guid><description>google
those-icons</description></item></channel></rss>