<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chronologies on Dinghy - FFV4</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/</link><description>Recent content in Chronologies on Dinghy - FFV4</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Resalage</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/resalage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/resalage/</guid><description>Resalage # Assessing the situation # Desalting is not a trivial matter. Depending on the conditions, you can hurt (and scare) yourself.
As soon as you surface, check for any loose ends or other objects that may be in your way. Locate where you are on the water and the time available for resurfacing: rocks, other boat. If you feel that you do not have the time to right the boat in the face of danger, give priority to people over equipment.</description></item><item><title>Bearing away from the buoy</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/abattee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/abattee/</guid><description>Bearing away from the buoy # Chronology # Slaughtered at the Buoy
Preparation: Put on the clear sheet Shock the hale low Slaughter: Slaughter and shock high End of the run: Raise the vertical stabilizer Start counter-heeling Trim from the edge Choke the cuningham Resume low pitch Think of tightening the buoy like a Formula 1 driver: with too tight a turn entry, you lose speed.</description></item><item><title>oloffee to the buoy</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/oloffee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/oloffee/</guid><description>L&amp;rsquo;oloffée à la bouée # Chronology # Oloffee at the Buoy
Descent: Reef in to arrive under the correct tack. Preparation: Put the daggerboard back on Take up the edge Take up the cuningham Oloffee: Border the sheet Loffer End of the oloffee Resume low hale Remember to tighten the buoy like a Formula 1 driver: with a too tight turn entry, you lose speed.</description></item><item><title>Tacking and gybing</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/tacking_and_gybing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/tacking_and_gybing/</guid><description>Tacking and gybing # Tacking and gybing are the basic dinghy maneuvers. We differentiate between classic maneuvers and rocking maneuvers. Tilting is an exaggeration of what is done naturally in strong winds. All you have to do is reproduce this movement.
Tacking # The tack is a strategic maneuver in dinghy sailing, it can make you lose or gain places. Often during a wind shift, the correct execution of a tack can give you an advantage over your competitors.</description></item><item><title>Man overboard</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/man_overboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/man_overboard/</guid><description>Man overboard # General # Recovering a HLM is not a trivial task under any circumstances.
The mass of a laser with its crew is around 150 kg. Even at a few knots, on the head of a person in the water the shock can be fatal. If the HLM has fallen into the water conscious you will want to recover it consciously.
The HLM is a maneuver to be adapted according to the conditions, it will be necessary to adapt, you will be the only judge.</description></item><item><title>Mast grabbing</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/mast_grabbing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/mast_grabbing/</guid><description>Taking the mast # In some cases (crew too light and tired, need to go fast&amp;hellip;) it is necessary to help a boat to resalt by lifting its mast from the water.
This maneuver is quite technical and usually reserved for the instructor.
Poorly executed, it can become dangerous. Before attempting it, be sure you know how to stop at a specific point.
Depending on the position of the desalinated boat, arrive so that it finishes its maneuver facing the wind.</description></item><item><title>Towing under sail after a dismasting</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/dematage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/chronologies/dematage/</guid><description>Towing after a dismasting # It happens that the dinghy dismasts, it can happen because of a mast breakage (on the laser at the sleeve) or because of a mast foot breakage. In any case, it is impressive and should not be taken lightly.
Preparation of the tow # The list of operations to perform (this list is not exhaustive):
Make sure all crew are okay. Check where the current is coming from.</description></item></channel></rss>