<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Weather forecast on Dinghy - FFV4</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/</link><description>Recent content in Weather forecast on Dinghy - FFV4</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>General circulation</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/general_circulation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/general_circulation/</guid><description>General Circulation # Explanation of temperature differences on earth # Earth-sun diagram
The sun provides almost all of our energy.
The energy balance of the Earth is zero: the Earth sends back into space all the energy it receives.
However, the energy received by the Earth is not uniform depending on the latitude.
The equator receives more energy than the poles. This will create warmer and colder areas.</description></item><item><title>Wind</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/wind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/wind/</guid><description>The wind # Balance of the winds # Wind is a flow of air. It moves globally from high pressure to low pressure. The greater the difference (gradient) in pressure (for a given distance), the stronger the wind. Pressure difference
Influence of the Coriolis force # Isobaric map
The wind moves parallel to the isobars (without taking friction into account): this is the geostrophic wind: balance between the pressure forces and the Coriolis force.</description></item><item><title>Air masses</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/air_volumes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/air_volumes/</guid><description>Air masses # Here are the main air masses found in Western Europe that shape the weather we have.
Definition of a stable and unstable air mass # In the atmosphere, air that rises or sinks because it is forced to do so is said to be unstable. If it does not move vertically, or only slightly, it is said to be stable. Thus, if we heat air, its tendency will be to rise, it becomes unstable.</description></item><item><title>Clouds</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/clouds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/clouds/</guid><description>Clouds # A cloud is composed of water or ice droplets. The air is completely saturated.
Types of cooling # To saturate air (at almost constant pressure), it must be cooled. There are 4 types of cooling:
Frontal Frontal cooling
Two air masses of different properties (warm and cold) meet. They do not mix. The warmer one is forced to rise (it is the lighter one).</description></item><item><title>Frontology</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/frontology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/frontology/</guid><description>Frontology # The front # A front is a region of the troposphere constituting a dynamic and thermal transition zone between two air masses with different characteristics (Source: Météo-France).
A front is a surface of discontinuity (transition zone) where two air masses with different properties confront each other. There are different types of fronts:
warm fronts, cold fronts, occluded fronts, stationary fronts. cold front Cold front</description></item><item><title>Time associated with a disturbance</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/weather_associated_with_a_perturbation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/weather_associated_with_a_perturbation/</guid><description>Time associated with a disturbance # Satellite view of a depression # Cold front
Disruption seen from above
Very often, the cloud structure of a disturbance allows you to distinguish several parts. The head is located in front of the disturbance. The body corresponds closely to the fronts. The warm sector is the warm air trapped between the warm and cold fronts.</description></item><item><title>isobaric map</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/isobaric_map/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/isobaric_map/</guid><description>The isobaric map # Presentation # The isobaric map represents the current or forecasted barometric situation with the position of the fronts. There are several types of maps: the surface map (which represents the pressure at sea level) and the altitude maps (representing the geopotential altitude at a given pressure), however the altitude maps are more complex to interpret. A surface isobaric map can be plotted, that is, with wind and pressure readings.</description></item><item><title>Local weather</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/local_weather/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/local_weather/</guid><description>Local weather # The coastal thermal breeze # The coastal thermal breezes are related to the interaction water / land: the thermal capacities of water and land are very different, they will therefore heat and cool at different speeds.
The sea is almost stable in temperature over 24 hours, while the land heats up during the day and cools down at night. This difference in temperature is at the origin of the breeze.</description></item><item><title>Modèles méteo</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/weather_models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/weather_models/</guid><description>Modèles méteo # Meteorological models are tools that allow us to predict the evolution of weather in the future.
They are based on complex mathematical calculations that take into account current conditions and wind and wave forecasts.
They are used by sailors to predict sailing conditions and by racers to predict race conditions.
Les informations à rechercher # L&amp;rsquo;origine # Weather models are produced by national or international weather services.</description></item><item><title>waves and the swell</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/waves_and_swell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/waves_and_swell/</guid><description>The waves and the swell # Definitions # Swell: sea of wind that has left its generating area Wave: sea of local wind The fetch is the distance over which the wind acts to create the waves. Wave length: distance between two crests of a wave train Formation # Birth of swell and waves
Creation of waves over the entirety of the world&amp;rsquo;s seas After the wind weakens or the waves spread outside the windy area, they spread freely, which is then called the swell Modification of waves in the vicinity of the coast by the presence of the bottom; As soon as the sea depth is less than about twice the height of the waves, they break on the beach or shoals.</description></item><item><title>Weather Report</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/weather_report/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/meteorology/weather_report/</guid><description>The weather report # In order to help the sailor know what the weather will be like, each country is required to have a weather service. MétéoFrance issues weather reports on a regular basis (see MétéoFranceMarine Guide).
There are 4 types of bulletins according to the type of activity: shore, coast, open sea and open sea. The coastal bulletin is the one we are interested in. This bulletin is issued by a CROSS three times a day by VHF.</description></item></channel></rss>