<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>🏁 The regatta on Dinghy - FFV4</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/</link><description>Recent content in 🏁 The regatta on Dinghy - FFV4</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting a good start</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/getting_off_to_a_good_start/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/getting_off_to_a_good_start/</guid><description>A good start consists in crossing the line as soon as possible after the start. But it is not enough, you also have to start: that is to say with as much speed as possible.
You must observe the other competitors and the elements (wind, currents) and use them to your advantage.
Here is a video that explains how to position yourself for a starboard tack start. In the video below, you can see the importance of starting with speed, when all the racers are grouped together on the line, they are all sailing in a shifty, turbulent wind.</description></item><item><title>Main rules</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/main_rules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/main_rules/</guid><description>Helm privileges # Rule 10 - Starboard tack priority # The sailboat in black shall not force the white to maneuver
When two sailboats pass each other while sailing in opposite directions, the one on starboard tack (receiving the wind from starboard) has priority. The sailboat on the port tack must then maneuver so as not to interfere with the other. Rule 11 - Leeward Priority # The windward sailboat shall not interfere with the leeward sailboat</description></item><item><title>Regatta flags</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/flags/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/flags/</guid><description>The race committee symbolizes one end of the starting line - on land or at sea. The orange flag indicates that the line is anchored. A buoy establishes the other end.
From one regatta to another, the duration of the starting procedure may vary. Most often, it is a countdown in minutes.
The race committee will conduct the starting procedure using flags and sound signals, in accordance with the &amp;ldquo;Instructions of Sailing&amp;rdquo; (IC) which must be broadcast to all.</description></item><item><title>Laylines</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/laylines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/regatta/laylines/</guid><description>The frame # During a regatta you can imagine a diamond between the windward and the leeward buoy: the frame.
This frame designates the limit course from which we make excess course. Within the frame, not all routes are equal, indeed, when tacking we lose some time and speed.
The frame designates the most direct route for the least number of maneuvers
If you want to reach the windward buoy with a single tack, the route taken will be the edge of the frame.</description></item></channel></rss>