<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on Dinghy - FFV4</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on Dinghy - FFV4</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Appendix: Recognizing clouds</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/clouds_recognition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/clouds_recognition/</guid><description>Appendix: Recognizing clouds&amp;rdquo; # A distinction is made between layered or stratiform clouds and ball or cumuliform clouds.
On the altitude side, the names of the highest clouds are composed with the prefix &amp;ldquo;cirro&amp;rdquo;, those of medium altitude with the prefix &amp;ldquo;alto&amp;quot;:
in the lower stage (from the ground to 2 km altitude), we encounter stratus (S) and stratocumulus (Sc). in the middle stage (from 2 to 5 or even 7 km of altitude), the altocumulus (Ac) and the altostratus (As).</description></item><item><title>Appendix: the fronts</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/annexe-fronts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/annexe-fronts/</guid><description>Annex: the fronts # Source: lavionnaire.fr
Definition # It is a region of the troposphere constituting a dynamic and thermal transition zone between two air masses different by their characteristics. Source : Météo-France A front is a surface of discontinuity (transition zone) where two air masses with different properties confront each other. There are different types of fronts:
warm fronts, cold fronts, occluded fronts, stationary fronts. Front schema</description></item><item><title>Self-Evaluation</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/self-evaluation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/self-evaluation/</guid><description>Self-assessment # This is the evaluation framework of the Fédération Française de Voile.
It is important to take your time and move on to the next level when you have mastered the previous one perfectly because the steps are designed to be consistent with the learning progression. But keep in mind that this is only a guide, and everyone progresses differently.
Be humble, there is no point in working on regatta strategies if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how to do a tack and master the exit angle, going backwards can allow you to &amp;ldquo;back up to jump&amp;rdquo; and ultimately make your progress faster.</description></item><item><title>Appendix: Rigging a laser</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/laser_rigging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/laser_rigging/</guid><description>Appendix: Rigging a laser # Prepare the sail # Place the material on a flat surface and check that you are not missing any parts Unroll the sail Thread the mast bottom and top in the axis, the two arrows must be aligned Slide the sail on the mast, the tack must be on the axis of the arrows and the mullet screw Put the battens in their respective places, the smallest on top.</description></item><item><title>proper use of a motorboat</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/motorboat_usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/motorboat_usage/</guid><description>The proper use of a motorboat # Before starting the engine # Do a check-up of the boat # All lines are coiled and stowed. No lines are dragging in the water. Hull plugs are closed. Moorings are securely stowed. Check the engine # The feeder is full and connected to the engine. The vent (small opening on the fuel cap allowing air to enter) is open.</description></item><item><title>Appendix: Anchoring your safety boat</title><link>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/safety_boat_mooring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://armandfardeau.github.io/dinghy-ffv4/en/docs/annexes/safety_boat_mooring/</guid><description>Dinghy: Anchoring your safety boat # To anchor your boat, you generally have two moorings:
A main anchor, heavy, at the front, consisting of an anchor with its chain and line, a line struck at the front of the boat. A secondary, light anchor, at the stern, consisting of a small anchor and a line. Remember that what ensures that an anchor holds well is not so much the anchor as the length of chain placed on the bottom.</description></item></channel></rss>